Divided by war. United by love.
Testament of Youth is a history, drama, war film directed by James Kent.
Testament of Youth is a powerful story of love, war and remembrance, based on the First World War memoir by
Vera Brittain, which has become the classic testimony of that war from a woman’s point of view.
A searing journey from youthful hopes and dreams to the edge of despair and back again, it’s a film
about young love, the futility of war and how to make sense of the darkest times.
Vera Brittain, played by Alicia Vikander.
Roland Leighton, played by Kit Harington.
Edward Brittain, played by Taron Egerton.
Victor Richardson, played by Colin Morgan.
Mr. Brittain, played by Dominic West.
Mrs. Brittain, played by Emily Watson.
Testament of Youth is a 2014 British drama film based on the First World
War memoir of the same name written by Vera Brittain.
The film stars Alicia Vikander as Vera Brittain, an independent young woman who
abandoned her studies at Somerville College, Oxford, to become a war nurse.
The film was directed by James Kent and written by Juliette Towhidi.
The film explores themes of nurse, world war i, poetry, pacifism, flanders.
The tone is dark and emotional.